# Mohamed Helal

Cairo, Egypt



mohammedhelalca@gmail.com



01145548540



linkedin.com/in/mohamed-helal-19723522a

## **Summary**

I'm an urban design and planning Bachelor's degree graduate, worked for 5 years in the field of landscape as a designer and a contractor, NOW I'm shifting my career to the web development field and starting by learning new technologies of web development as a full-stack web developer.

For now, I have well hands-on knowledge in frontend web development and I'm looking forward to developing my knowledge into a great experience by penetrating the market of web development as a new candidate.

### **Experience**



### Web Developer

Mosaic Shop

Jan 2022 - Present (7 months +)

I'm working as a part-time web developer with Mosaic shop company to develop an e-commerce website for the products they are willing to sell online.

### **Operations Manager**

Elnour-med for Construction

Jan 2020 - Present (2 years 7 months +)

Working as an operation manager in the construction field of landscape and building with responsibilities:

- 1- Developing construction drawings.
- 2- Maintain on-site work.
- 3- Keeping track of the construction process as scheduled.
- 4- Developing BOQs for construction projects.
- 5- Developing tenders for construction projects.
- 6- Coordinating with other contractors and workers.
- 7- Developing price lists and cost estimations for projects.

## **ECG** Landscape Architect

Engineering Consultants Group S.A.

Dec 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 1 month)

I worked as a Landscape architect at ECG with the following responsibilities:

- 1- Develop landscape working drawings.
- 2- Develop landscape construction drawings.
- 3- Develop BOQs and schedules for landscape projects.
- 4- Develop reports and presentations for projects.

# GATEWAY

## **Landscape Architect**

**GATEWAY** for Urban Development

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 11 months)

I worked as a junior Landscape architect at Gateway for Urban Development with the following responsibilities:

- 1- Create a landscape design ideas.
- 2- Develop landscape working drawings.
- 3- Develop landscape construction drawings.

#### **Education**



### Cairo University

Diploma of Education, City/Urban, Community and Regional Planning Jun 2017 - Jun 2018 This is a postgraduate Diploma

# Cairo University

Bachelor's degree, City/Urban, Community and Regional Planning Jun 2011 - Jun 2016

### **Licenses & Certifications**

- Certified Professional Autodesk 3ds Max 2013 CLS Learning Solutions
- ArcGIS Desktop Professional 10.1 CLS Learning Solutions
- Adobe Photoshop CS5 CLS Learning Solutions
- Adobe Illustrator CS5 CLS Learning Solutions
- Adobe InDesign CC 2015 CLS Learning Solutions
- Certified Professional AutoCAD 2013 CLS Learning Solutions
- Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 AMIT Learning
- Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript Udemy
- Challenger Track of egypt fwd with Udacity Udacity
- **IELTS 7.0** IELTS Official

#### Skills

HTML5 • User Experience Design (UED) • Adobe Photoshop • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

• JavaScript • Bootstrap • jQuery • Landscape Design • Management